EHAB ABDELAAL IBRAHIM

CAREER HISTORY





https://brairahotels.com/

nternational Trade Holdings Company

https://www.ithc.com.kw/

Executive Housekeeper

BRAIRA HOTELS (ALNAKHEEL 5 STARS)
FROM 07- JAN 2020 TO 22 MARCH 2021

Cluster Executive Housekeeper

INN & GO HOTELS ****, Convention Center & Royal Suites**** Kuwait- HUMA Island Resort & Spa***** Philippine

SUMMARY

I am a hospitality professional with proven experience in the Middle East & Asia. I worked in 4 and 5 stars international and local chain hotels and resorts, successful opening of two 5- stars hotel in very competitive and challenging environments. Extensive experience in resorts and business hotels with several openings, rebranding and renovations



Executive Housekeeper

SWISS BELHOTEL **** 4 stars - KUWAIT May 2014 to Jan 2016

RESPONSIBILITIES

https://www.swiss-belhotel.com/

Implement strategies aimed at cost minimization, without reduction of quality standards.

Ensure operation runs within out looked financial framework.

Purchase operational supplies as required within budget and outlook.

Implement and maintain training systems to ensure that associates have the necessary framework and skills to perform efficiently and effectively.

Oversee the inspection of VIP rooms, Suites and villas

Providing on-going coaching the housekeeping teams to comply with all ITHC brand standards and to reach the highest guest satisfaction possible.

Developing and putting into operation the current system and technical advancement in the field of Laundry operations.

Develop new methods for increasing laundry efficiency.

Oversee the laundry equipment preventive maintenance program.

Recruit and train new employees.

Ensure routine maintenance is carried out in your areas of responsibility.

Plans the work for the department and distributes assignments accordingly.

Control all linen stocks and levels, ensuring linen costs are controlled in accordance with hotel procedures and Fully aware of budgeted

PERSONAL INFORMATION

MOBILE NO: +966 568252728

EMAIL: Ehabaal2010@yahoo.com

SKYPE ID: Ehabaal2010 NATIONALITY EGYPTIAN

DATE OF BIRTH 1ST- JULY 1979

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ehababdalaal-13170891/

OBJECTIVE

Takes the responsibility for the planning, organization, development and direction for overall operation of the housekeeping and laundry in accordance with and federal, state, and local standards and guidelines, all work will be in line with departmental guidelines, the departmental business plan, and corporate guidelines and service concepts, to assure that the highest

degree of quality resident care is maintained at all times. Monitors the financial performance of the

CAREER HISTORY



<u>Assistant Executive Housekeeper</u>

Melia Dubai 5 ***** Pre- Opening November 2012 till March 2014



Assistant Housekeeping Manager

H hotel DUBAI 5***** Pre-opening January 2010 till April 2011

https://www.hhoteldubai.com/

RESPONSIBILITIES

Make regular room and public area inspections with the Engineering Department on deviation from standard set ups and maintenance, to follow up on the Out of Order and Out of Service rooms.

Directly responsible for ensuring that proper training of associates is done such that associate has the necessary skill to perform duties with maximum efficiency and drafts training schedules for the month based on guidelines set by the department head and drafts presents by service leaders, and recommends planned training activities.

Conduct appraisal sessions for supervised associates and formally documents performance for the period using official forms, following procedures and observing set timelines as disseminated by HR.

Oversee the implementation of control procedures for expenses and ensures that these are consistently implemented in all HK sections.

Ensure that all employees are treated fairly and consistently as outlined in their terms and conditions of employment, local legislation, and company / hotel policies and procedures.

obtaining the highest quality of cleanliness in the hotel, and to provide efficient, prompt, courteous, trouble free and proactive service to customers; hence maximizing guest satisfaction. All work will be in line with departmental guidelines, the departmental business plan, and corporate guidelines and service expectations.

CAREER HISTORY



https://www.hhoteldubai.com/



https://www.redseahotels.com



https://www.redseahotels.com



https://www.redseahotels.com

Senior Housekeeping Supervisor

H hotel Dubai 5**** Pre-opening April 2008 till January 2010

Housekeeping Supervisor

H hotel Dubai 5**** Pre-opening

July 2007 till April 2008

Housekeeping Supervisor

Grand Resort Hurghada Egypt ***** 5

Pre- opening

July 2004 to March 2007

Housekeeping Coordinator

Grand Resort Hurghada Egypt ***** 5

Pre- Opening

January 2004 to July 2004

Housekeeping Order Taker

Grand Resort Hurghada Egypt ***** 5

Pre- Opening

January 2003 to December 2003

EDUCATION

B.A of English literature, Almenoufia University, Egypt at 2002.

CERTIFICATES

ICDL computer skills.

Manager of the year Award- 2015

HACAP certificate

Fire Drill

Evacuation Training

Handling Guest Complaints

REFERENCE







NAME IRFAN ULISLAM
POSITION HOTEL MANAGER
MOBILE NO 00971 50 501 2921

EMAIL <u>Irfan.ulislam@melia.com</u>

sofirfan@gmail.com

NAME SEOW HEE LOH

POSITION Executive Housekeeper EMAIL lohseowhee@hotmail.com

NAME Pierre E. Fares

POSITION Director of Operation-Hotels

MOBILE NO 00965 900 21497

EMAIL Pierre fares@hotmail.com

pierre.fares@ithc.com.kw